Cecil Thomas

Taylorsville, UT 84129 (435) 668-2486 me@cecil-thomas.com github.com/kitsune21

WEBSITES

Cecil-Thomas.com - Built using React.js with Typescript. Over 80% unit test coverage. Uses a custom built terminal-like interface to allow the users to execute commands to learn more about myself, and projects that I have worked on.

Journeys.Cafe - Built using React.js, Node.js, and postgres. Hosted using Netlify and Supabase (Auth and db). Full CI/CD pipeline that allows me to push out new changes and features in less than a minute. Steadily growing user base. Over 60% unit test coverage.

Frozenspade.Tv - Built using React.js and hosted on Netlify. Uses the SpeedRun.com api to pull in data on currently held world records for the Twitch streamer "Frozenspade". Full CI/CD pipeline between GitHub and Netlify to allow for rapid deployments.

EXPERIENCE

Entrata, Lehi — Software Developer 1

March 2021 - Current

Led the prototyping and development of the first new features using React/Typescript to speed up the user experience. Worked on projects that refactored and removed no longer used code, and added in unit test coverage using the PHPUnit framework.

Entrata, Lehi - Software Development Manager

June 2020 - March 2021

Worked with more than 38 developers, QA members, and product managers across two teams to develop, test, and release projects and new feature offerings for clients. Worked with my teams to reduce the open bug backlog from over 100 to less than 20. Helped teams in the development of new products that leveraged machine learning.

EDUCATION

DevPoint Labs, Salt Lake City

Aug 2019 - October 2019

Desert Hills High School, St. George

Aug 2008 - May 2011

SKILLS

ReactJS

NodeJS

C#

PostgreSQL

AWS

Ruby on Rails

PHP

AWARDS

Eagle Scout Rank

Louis Armstrong Jazz Award

John Phillips Sousa Award

LANGUAGES

English

Japanese

Spanish (Basic)